so today I'm going to be staying in one
of the most iconic hotels in the world
costing over 1 billion pounds to build
and situated on its own private island
the burjell Arab is a global icon of
Arabian luxury I'm gonna see what it's
like to spend a night check out the pool
the food and so much more
so people are pulling up here in Range
Rovers in really luxury cars I'm pulling
up in my higher car
which is a uh like a little Fiat Punto a
bit embarrassing oh my God look at the
cars here
I think I must be the worst car here so
I do get free parking with my stay they
will literally park the car for me
thank you
[Music]
just been handed this
so these are supposed to be hot this is
cold smells nice thing check-in is
taking around about 15 minutes I think
this is the longest time I've ever took
to check into anything I'm quite sure
what they're doing a credit card
I don't know if the camera does that in
justice but that is so
big
the actorium is considered as one of the
tallest among the world it is 180 meter
high as you see as it goes higher you
can see the uh the colors change so it
represents the four elements of the
Earth
so room 1607
I think I should go in and check it out
now I'm going to try to not say wow too
many times so this Suite is on two
levels the first level and then an upper
level straight away there is a toilet
down here
just in case you have guests look at
those lights
everything that you see is real gold and
just look how easy
it is to press
however that looks a little bit out of
place in here
not quite sure what that is
I've got a b day and the sink some
tissues I love how they put the flannels
like that it's really nice I've just
seen this and I can control the TV sound
all over the apartment wow that's how we
turn the lights off
like that
so whilst I'm here if I really wanted to
I could sit at my own desk there's even
an option to uh to have a MacBook Pro
obviously not to keep but to use it for
work
champagne please now also there is a
very nice Burj Al Arab pen I wonder how
many people take these and they charge
it onto your bill and a notepad to jot
some stuff down now if I open this
here is where I've got my
my tea and coffee
I love how it's all laid out look sugar
is in see-through little cellophane bags
how all the milk is laid out there's for
the coffee machine and of course some
tea
little cups there's even a teapot there
and I've got the choice of look at that
we can buy these as well a Burj Al Arab
Tassimo now yes I am going to be picky
for the price I paid for the room but
this kettle
is pretty bulk standard
in it plastic nothing special and
against that
at least it's clean so this is my little
bar area everything I've been told on
the top is complementary there is a mini
bar and I don't know whether this is
censored or not so I don't want to lift
anything out but I've got tomato juice
Coca-Cola oh orange juice tonic water
we've got a couple of beers of course
some champagne
here
oh I've got some Gin some whiskey I
wonder how much these sweets and
chocolates are there's even shortbread
rounds in there the menu is here
obviously it's all in dirhams I'm sure
someone will tell me in the comments how
much this is because uh I don't know how
to work it out in my head to be honest
because champagne is 580 Dirhams we will
leave that because we get some
complimentary snacks oh a little
envelope see what this says look at that
it's like a little Christmas card for
the Burj Al Arab dear Tim it's a
pleasure to welcome you and I would like
to thank you for choosing the burjal
Arab as your home away from home so not
well it is but my home's not like this
the team is joining me to wish you a
wonderful stay kind regards the general
manager what is this look how cute they
are I kind of don't want to touch them
let's try this one first
okay I thought they were dessert but
that was nutty creamy Savory please tell
me that that is not what I think it is
if it is I've never tried caviar before
with a um I'm not on top of it looks
like a salmon mousse on a tiny little
bit of bread here we go I'll go all in
wow that's nice got a couple of sweets
and some Burj Al Arab orange juice I
love it when you stay in these Posh
hotels and you get lids for the glasses
totally unnecessary but actually it's
quite nice so let's check out my sitting
room as it were if I've got friends over
which I don't and there's even some
plates laid out here I can actually is
that ow I know that sounds stupid but
yes this is all real fruit pineapple
peaches oranges grapes kiwi and this is
my living room
wow I'm just absolutely
blown away by this room
it is incredible and what's even more
incredible when the camera adjusts
is the view
and if I pan down there you can see the
simple but the views are spectacular
over downtown Dubai
question is is you know which seat do I
choose because they're all really comfy
ah this is feather I think so you really
do sink into it also got a change launch
is that what you call it
the nice side table so the TV down here
is pretty huge here is my remote in a
little leather case the remote is
branded with this I can control my
curtains as well so if I hit that one
it closes my curtains obviously Standard
TV with movies and uh other stuff what's
this
yeah there's a DVD player in there for
those people that still use DVDs hard to
imagine how all this is
gold well that's downstairs I might as
well show you upstairs there's obviously
air conditioning there's a vase there
with no flowers in it but let's let's
take you up there's a room here what's
in here
a secret room
there's a door
oh for storage and the mirror
but let's head upstairs there's lights
going up the stairs and a pretty big
chandelier too mirrors feature a lot in
this apartment again I think these are
all for the lights aren't they
yes
three different dimmer switches
so the bedroom is on the right
bathroom is on the left
and I guess a room to do
your makeup with a nice little seat here
I think in the drawers
look at them vanity mirror
got a bag another bag
and laundry bags oh right so they can do
dry cleaning how often do you get shoe
horns anymore now when I first saw this
I thought these were like cigars I'm
quite sure what this is I'm sure Gabby
would tell me but something to do with
makeup maybe I don't know the hairdryer
look at that a Dyson that's also gold
plated
there's storage look at the hangers
version Arab hangers everywhere that's
what I mean the attention to detail I've
got a safe and also a flashlight that's
quite a big safety I've got some
flip-flops
some version flip-flops I might use them
because I actually don't have any this
is insane all for one person tonight
obviously normally a couple in here
oh I've got some robes very nice just
this door look how shiny
that is
all polished
odd place to have a bench
and a mirror is facing down which is
quite nice so lots to show you in the
bathroom and I don't know how much of
this is complementary that I can take
away but after shaving balm some Hermes
odored to toilette that's expensive
stuff isn't it but just look at these
Taps all gold
some flannels skin care Gabby would love
that his and her sinks look at the
towels
embroidered as well and just to make you
feel even more paranoid whilst you're
here on holiday they've got some
weighing scales a gold bin I'm very
disappointed about the phone I thought
the phone would be a little bit better
than this
I love how they wrap up the toilet roll
as well very nice the bath and I'm not
over exaggerating is ridiculously huge
so hot
cold
not quite sure what that is this is a
Jacuzzi bath this is how big the bath is
it's a Jacuzzi bath I can't wait to use
it later however you won't want to see
that this shower is literally
so huge
you could fit five people in here
again I'm very confused with all these
oh
okay so that's the temperature that
switches that on and these switch these
on to do other areas and there's also
like a little hand shower I'm actually
surprised about the shower it's not as
big as I thought more complimentary
shower gel and shampoo and look at all
that free stuff I've got a Nail Care a
comb dental kit a vanity kit not quite
sure what that is a shower cap and a
shaving kit also plenty of towels now
it's not very often that I actually take
away the free stuff that you get in a
hotel but I definitely will be doing
that here anyway let's check out the
bedroom
I need some lights on where's the lights
are they oh they're here
so a little living room in my bedroom
which I've always liked I'd love to have
a big enough house to do that look at
that a little Buffet to put your legs on
whilst you're relaxing your living room
just look at the bin
this is leather
all that gold polish this is um
different
it's also a seat stroke a table now the
bed
yes I'm gonna say the word wow
because
that is just
insane
and
not that I am bothered about it but it's
got a mirror on the top that can luxury
these curtains
how they feel
and once again you get some amazing
views
over the uh the Persian Gulf
people there jet skiing you can actually
see over to the wild islands that are
just over there they're building a new
hotel there so this will look amazing
later I will show you this View later on
tonight
but where's the TV
it should be here so how do I get the TV
up
TV
on off
the TV's there how does it how does it
go up have I got a control or something
is there a button here I press okay I'm
gonna have to figure out how I get the
TV to come up
because I don't know
wow look at that it's nice
oh there's a mini fridge in here
another mini fridge let's do the bed
test oh oh yes this may be the comfiest
bed I think I've ever sat on I'll let
you know how the Sleep goes just look at
these cushions they're huge obviously
well some people might like to sleep on
these I don't but the pillows are
equally big I feel like I need to get
some firmer pillows though the headboard
is pretty huge and again it's leather I
didn't notice that there's also a mirror
behind the headboard and these really
luxury silk curtains now the only
criticism I've got of the bedroom is
again what is the deal with the phones
phone looks plastic well it is plastic
and it looks really old in fact
it's even a little bit dirty so they're
going to polish all the gold and Hoover
it make it all look lovely but then have
these really grubby phones what's that
about however a gold pencil bedside
table
I've got some slippers
I should have put them on first
again this bedside table look at that
what's around the other side
pretty much the same and for the other
person staying in your room
there's more of these I'm definitely
going to take these well that is my room
tour now something that's rather
exciting considering that you do pay a
lot for this room the butler told me
that I get well first of all 24-hour
Butler and also I get happy hour I can
order any alcoholic drink and have it in
the room as many as I want as long as
it's between five and eight o'clock I
think but they don't do champagne on
that offer I might have a glass of white
wine or maybe a whiskey we'll go and
check out the rest of the hotel because
there's a swimming pool upstairs there's
a spa but also the outside swimming pool
looks crazy an infinity pool out over
the gulf I've got to go and check it out
let's go even the do not disturb on the
door is like leather
anyway bye for now room
just want to quickly go up there because
apparently that's uh the money shot up
there which way do I go over here to the
lifts
look at the carpet
sorry you're hearing the uh the Flop and
the flip of my flip-flops
pretty quick lifts can you hear that
they move up pretty quick I'm enjoy them
on floor 16.
absolutely smells really lovely up here
wow good afternoon
wow
I'll definitely have to come for a swim
up here later but look at the views you
get
yikes look at the beach down there
this is crazy
however we've got that big pool outside
I'm not gonna be spending too much time
in here
wow if you don't like heights you're not
gonna like this
my God
that does my eyes in
that doesn't even look real
people are like ants down there
you can see all the floors is this
like the new treatment that we are
focusing on the brain yeah yeah you will
sit in the zero cavity share did you say
zero gravity yeah so you float
like really yeah
yeah wow how much is that this one if
I'm not wrong is 450.
minutes for 25 minutes can I have a look
in there or is it locked oh wow okay
so let's head out onto the pool
and the heat hits you
now the old pool used to be here I
believe
because that was before
that this seven star hotel had a big
pool and this huge Sun deck that
stretches out into the Arabian Gulf
actually came here from I think it was
the Netherlands or Denmark or something
it traveled by boat thousands of miles
to be put here it's obviously as this is
a civilized Hotel we're supposed to get
changed when we come down rather than
come down in our
swimming gear
this is a fresh water pool and a
saltwater pool
I think this might be the uh the fresh
water pool where the kids can play
this is the part I've been looking
forward to trying
the infinity pool I have to get my GoPro
on and check it out
and this is quite handy because I didn't
bring any sun cream with me but they
actually have got Sun cream and after
sun which is quite handy
wow
so for the price you pay for the room
which I'll come to at the end you feel
like you really need to cram everything
and keep now luckily I was able to check
in early around about midday but most
rooms are not available until three
o'clock you can use the facilities up
until midday tomorrow and they have a
beach club as well and a private beach
which I'll probably use then but for now
I think uh perhaps I'll just relax and
go for a swim with my embarrassing
yellow shorts that I got from Primark
now I'm not quite sure how much it costs
for a sun bed so I better find out
see if I can get my towels while I'm
down there I don't have to pay any extra
and they have these amazing Cabanas that
also have Sea View balconies
they're open to go and have a look in
but look you can see outside of some
food
grab a sunbed
just have a quick look in here no one's
stopping me
you get more complimentary drinks and
food a huge TV
and
balcony
what the heck
[Applause]
so private sunbeds and yes of course
this does come at an extra cost I think
it's around about three four hundred
pounds for the afternoon so I won't be
doing that so this is the changing rooms
for the pool
wow
a body lotion shaving stuff even some
hair gel
and then you just choose one of these to
get changed in not only do you get
changed in them but they've also got
their own shower
with body wash or shampoo so I have just
been told that the sun beds I can sit
wherever I want they're all
complementary so I might as well
lay here oh and another thing
got these little tablets
and I can press the service
and I want a drink
however that'll probably get very
expensive
in these are fresh complementary water
that is chilled and they come around and
they top these up for you
I feel really bad because I keep saying
is this complimentary is this
complimentary
after the price I paid for the room
we'll find out why
it never looks that glamorous when you
look over the other side so for lunch I
have decided to go for and actually this
is reasonably priced I went for a
lobster roll I get a little mini
mayonnaise and ketchup
and some fries as well
okay let's talk dinner so there is a
Michelin star restaurant here which does
six courses for 246 pounds probably not
going to go for that
this place looks amazing
looking over
I think it's jamiro beach in Palm
Jumeirah over in that direction now
although you can't swim in the pool I
don't think at night the restaurant
strip bar is still open there's a bar
over there that looks pretty quiet
well can you go in the pool I don't
think so the lights are on always looks
really pretty doesn't it with the lights
on
well the music is still playing I can
smell Shish is I think that's what's
going on around here so there's a an
Alfresco kind of restaurant out here
it's really warm tonight
also to eat in that restaurant right at
the top there is a dress code
is only for you right yeah thank you
thank you very much
let me move this light
it's a pizza at the end of the day
walking into the main lobby in the
evening
a couple of designer shops
far too expensive for my taste
and I think this actually looks better
during the day than it does at night
personally
of course it still looks totally amazing
and I just want to show you this this is
a buffet restaurant
but on the rather Posh expensive side
just gonna take a look so 450 Dirhams
per person
muscles
crab claws
grilled salmon
of a restaurant style
but in Buffet form smells nice
it's not my cup of tea though wow look
at the restaurants
they are nice it's a piano Lounge up
here look
very nice
overlooking the
dancing fountains which I thought they'd
be lit up at night but they're not just
look how that sparkles
I remember seeing a documentary on this
when it was first built and they were
worried about the humidity outside in
Dubai and that the humidity inside would
get to a point where everything would
get really wet or they could actually
have problems with little clouds forming
at the top
so let's show you the front of the hotel
at night see what it looks like honestly
that carpet is huge
and how they keep it so
amazingly colorful I don't know there's
fish on the wall here
and either side of the hotel lobby
they've got concierge
so if you need anything I've got a
private Butler I don't need to worry
about it
honestly there's no dirty spots here
how are you doing I'm okay am I allowed
to go for a walk down to the end of
course is that okay thank you so you see
these um Rolls-Royce Phantoms
now you can actually uh pick you up
from the airport if you wish you have to
pay a premium for it
doesn't look good from here we need to
get a little bit further out in fact I
think we can take a little buggy
let's find out hello am I can you take
me down to the beach
is that okay all right thank you
it's a security gates there pretty tight
can't get in without your name being on
the door
thank you
so this is the Burj Alara beach again
I'll check this out very briefly in the
morning but I just wanted to show you
what it looks like at night to see the
birds lit up even though it's getting on
a little bit the burjell Arab is still a
very beautiful hotel
but that was great I've never had a
whirlpool bath before
something I'm not used to but they offer
a turn down service basically they
Hoover
they put your slippers there for you
with a little what looks like a towel
and some mints no not mints
foot
gel an eye gel there's me thinking that
I have mints on the bed the bed is made
up ready for tonight
so I will see you in the morning
well morning all right summer sleep last
night was on the whole pretty good
although those pillows for me I'm not a
big fan of those big thick pillows where
your head sinks into them I just
unfortunately get too hot so I did ask
for some firmer pillows but they weren't
really that much firmer now breakfast is
downstairs but there is an option to
have breakfast
in the room this is what I've got for
breakfast so I went for poached eggs
some orange juice I've also got a coffee
for a cappuccino which I did I went for
waffles some fresh fruit and some toast
look at that I also get some little mini
bottles of Nutella and syrup that's
under there at the butter and also
there's this button there I just press
it for collection and I've laid it out
for me saying Bon Appetit more
condiments sugar a tea strainer why is
it that I feel guilty eating breakfast
in the room they do offer it so uh I
might as well take it try the orange
juice I was going to drink it out of
that as you can tell I'm not used to
this kind of living even the plates have
got gold around the edge I'll stick on
some hollandaise sauce
outside in
let's give it a try
I'm a little bit gutted that the uh the
egg didn't go out on that one
unfortunately
okay let's try the waffles so I've got
some Nutella maple syrup so this is my
first experience of ever having food in
the room like this and I would say there
is a downside and that is that uh the
food is only a lukewarm by the time you
start eating it like the toast is cold
already and these waffles are cold I
know I shouldn't be moaning yeah the
waffles are pretty cold so we wanted to
stay here for a very long time it's
taken me quite a while to save the state
in this hotel and in actual fact it's
not class it's a seven star hotel it's
actually only classed as a five-star
hotel but at the top of its game so
first of all let's start with the sweet
yes it was impressive I did say wow a
lot the 24 karat gold in the room was
totally amazing I was very surprised
about the telephones in the room how
cheap and plastic they were apparently
they have over 20 different types of
pillows however when I asked for a firm
pillow that was the only firm pillow
they can offer the TV didn't come up in
the bedroom as it should have done but
that was really it the pool is totally
amazing the staff can't do enough for
you and you you know for that price I
should think so too so how much did it
cost me to stay one night in this hotel
it cost me 1 500 pounds now when I'm at
the hotel they did ask my credit card
for extra expenses that I might incur
however I did take some peanuts out of
the mini bar that they didn't charge me
for they might realize that and then
send me the bill I did like the happy
hour free alcoholic drinks and whatever
Brands you wanted apart from Champagne
from five until eight that was actually
quite a nice touch is it overrated
I still think it's an amazing hotel but
now obviously in Dubai there are bigger
and better hotels like the one that's
just open up on the palm would I stay
here again I can't afford to do give the
video a thumbs up hit subscribe and tell
me in the comments would you stay here
I'll see you next time